Visual AIDS Artist Files
Visual AIDS Archive
- Francisco Diaz (b. 1950)
  Francisco Diaz first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain an artist's biography. These materials are dated 1998.
  - Box 15, Folder 9 (Box 15)
- Gustavo Diaz (b. 1973)
  Gustavo Diaz was born in 1973. His work includes painting, illustration, collage, and multimedia work.
  Materials pertaining to Gustavo Diaz include Postcards from the Edge submission materials. These materials are dated 2020.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/gustavo-diaz
  - Box A, Folder 7 (Box A)
- George Dinhaupt (b. 1955)
  George Dinhaupt was born in 1955 in Los Angeles, California. He works primarily in portraiture. It has been exhibited primarily in New York and California.
  George Dinhaupt first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2011. They contain Postcard from the Edge submission materials, a CD with images of artwork, exhibition announcements, CVs, ephemera, and an artist's statement. These materials are dated 2011-2019.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/george-dinhaupt
  - Box 15, Folder 11 (Box 15)
- Scott DiStefano (b. 1963)
  Scott DiStefano was born in 1963 in Omaha, Nebraska. He studied graphic design and art. His work is primarily painting and photography and has been exhibited in New York.
  Scott DiStefano first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2003. They include a printout of artwork dated 2003.
  - Box 15, Folder 12 (Box 15)
- Wiliam Donovan (b. 1953)
  William Donovan was born in 1953 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. He studied at the Fashion Institute of Technology and the School of Visual Arts in New York City. His work has been exhibited in New York. His work incorporates various mediums such as oil, wax, acrylic, pencil, ink, thread, sand, and collage to wood, canvas, or paper.
  William Donovan first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2001. They contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials, exhibition announcements, an artist's statement, a CV, photocopies of press clippings, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of artwork. These materials are dated 1999-2007.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/william-donovan
  - Box 15, Folder 13 (Box 15)
  - Box 16, Folder 1 (Box 16)
- durkART (b. 1960)
  durkART was born in 1960 in Chicago, Illinois and lives in Orlando. His paintings are based on joy and his experiences in the 1970s and 80s. His work has been exhibited in several galleries in the Orlando area.
  durkART first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2006. They contain exhibition announcements, correspondence, ephemera, artist's biography and CV, artwork on paper, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 2006-2021.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/durkart
  - Box 16, Folder 3 (Box 16)
- Chloe Dzubilo (1960–2011)
  Chloe Dzubilo was born in 1960 in Middletown, Connecticut. She moved to New York in 1982 where she briefly worked at Studio 54 before becoming the art director at the magazine East Village Eye. She was an artist, musician, model, and longtime activist for civil rights and healthcare rights for people with HIV, the trans community, and drug users. She passed away in 2011 in New York City.
  Chloe Dzubilo first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2011. They contain CDs with images of artwork, original artwork on paper, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, correspondence, zines, exhibition announcements, exhibition materials, artist's biography, memorial program and announcement, printout of digital content, and periodicals. These materials are dated 2004-2014.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/chloe-dzubilo
  - Box 16, Folder 4 (Box 16)
- Larry Eades (b. 1953)
  Larry Eades was born in 1953 in Tarrytown, New York. He works in photography and painting.
  Larry Eades first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain CDs with images of artwork, exhibition announcements, correspondence, artist's statement, calendar submission materials, photographic prints, photo proof sheets, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1992-2013.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/larry-eades
  - Box 16, Folder 5 (Box 16)
- Brent Nicholson Earle (b. 1951)
  Brent Nicholson Earle was born in 1951 in in Niagara Falls, New York. He is an artist and an early activist, notable for his long-distance runs to raise money for AIDS service organizations in the effort to promote AIDS awareness. Earle worked in New York City as an actor, writer, stage manager, lecturer, archivist, photographer, optical designer, curator, and art gallery administrator.
  Brent Nicholson Earle first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain a CV, an artist's statement, artist biographies, an installation proposal, correspondence, calendar submission materials, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1986-2005.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/brent-nicholson-earle
  - Box 16, Folder 6 (Box 16)
- Sean Earley (1953–1992)
  Sean Earley was born in 1953 and resided mostly in Texas. In addition to his fine art, mostly oil on canvas, his career was as a commercial illustrator. His work was exhibited in Texas and New York. He passed away in 1992.
  Materials pertaining to Sean Earley were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998 by Paul Bridgewater. They contain a CD with images of artwork, exhibition announcements, CVs, photocopies of press clippings, gallery materials, photographic print of artwork, a periodical, image lists, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1984-1992.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/sean-earley
  - Box 16, Folder 7 (Box 16)
- Per Eidspjeld (b. 1960)
  Per Eidspjeld was born in 1960 in Asker, Norway. He works in photography, video, installation, and mixed media.
  Per Eidspjeld first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1999. They contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1991-2012.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/per-eidspjeld
  - Box 17, Folder 1 (Box 17)
- Ed Eisenberg (1951–1997)
  Ed Eisenberg was born in 1951. He was involved in public art activism beginning with Political Art Documentation and Distribution and was also a core member of the artist collective REPOhistory. He passed away in 1997.
  Material pertaining to Ed Eisenberg were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 2000. They contain exhibition announcements, exhibition catalogs, postcards, press clippings, printouts of art, photocopies of journal articles, periodicals, a CD, CVs, memorial biography, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1989-2004.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/ed-eisenberg
  - Box 17, Folder 2 (Box 17)
  - Box 17, Folder 3 (Box 17)
- Garland Eliason-French (1942–1996)
  Garland Eliason-French was born in 1942 in Peoria, Illinois. She attended Sarah Lawrence College in Bronxvillle, New York, and received a BFA from Bradley University, and an MFA from the Art Institute of Chicago. She was a prolific artist of various media. She passed away in 1996.
  Materials pertaining to Garland Eliason-French were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1994 by William P French Jr. Additional materials were donated in 2019 by Laura Eliason. They contain correspondence, personal journals, personal photographs, exhibition catalogs, an obituary, periodicals, press clippings, address book contents, photographs of art, ephemera, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1965-1997.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/garland-eliason-french
  - Box 69, Folder 1 (Box 69)
  - Box 69, Folder 2 (Box 69)
  - Box 69, Folder 3 (Box 69)
  - Box 69, Folder 4 (Box 69)
  - Box C, Folder 13 (Box C)
- eljay (b. 1961)
  eljay was born in 1961 in Bay Shore, New York. He studied at Polytechnic Institute of New York. His work is primarily photography and has been exhibited in New York.
  eljay first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2011. They contain a CD with images of artwork and accompanying image list, and an exhibition announcement. These materials are dated 2007-2012.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/eljay
  - Box 17, Folder 4 (Box 17)
- Darrel Ellis (1958–1992)
  Darrel Ellis was born inThe Bronx in 1958 and lived and worked in New York City. He was a mixed-media artist known for his experimental approach to painting and photography. His work has been exhibited widely and is in the collections of the Museum of Modern Art, the Whitney Museum, and the Metropolitan Museum of Art, among others. He passed away in 1992.
  Materials pertaining to Darrel Ellis were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 2000 by Allen Frame. They include an exhibition program, an artist's book, photographs of artwork, correspondence, exhibition materials, printouts of artwork, a periodical, a catalog of art, publications, interview transcripts, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1990-2023.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/darrel-ellis
  - Box 17, Folder 5 (Box 17)
  - Box C, Folder 5 (Box C)
- Yigal Elyadin (b. 1950)
  Yigal Elyadin was born in 1950 in Tel Aviv, Israel and came to the United States in 1960. He was educated at the Philadelphia College of Art with a degree in Environmental Design. He worked in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania in the design field before devoting himself solely to making art.
  Yigal Elyadin first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain a biography, correspondence, ephemera, images lists, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1990-2000.
  - Box 17, Folder 6 (Box 17)
- John Engstrom (b. 1955)
  John Engstrom was born in 1955 in Boston, Massachusetts. He was educated at Boston University. His photography work has been exhibited in Massachusetts and New York.
  John Engstrom first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1999. They contain a CV, an artist's biography, correspondence, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1994-2000.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/john-engstrom
  - Box 17, Folder 7 (Box 17)
- James K. Fackrell (b. 1962)
  James K. Fackrell was born in 1962 in San Diego, California. He was educated at Fresno City College and the Student Arts League in New York. His work was exhibited widely in California and New York. His work includes photography, sculpture, and mixed media.
  James K. Fackrell first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2002. They contain an exhibition announcement, correspondence, a CV, artist's statements, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1988-2011.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/james-k.-fackrell
  - Box 17, Folder 8 (Box 17)
- Rotimi Fani-Kayode (1955–1989)
  Rotimi Fani-Kayode was born in 1955 in Lagos, Nigeria. His family moved to the UK in 1966. He received a BA from Georgetown University and an MFA from Pratt Institute before moving back to the UK where he lived until his death. He worked primarily in photography, including large-scale portraits focusing on the black male body. He passed away in 1989.
  Material pertaining to Rotimi Fani-Kayode include exhibition announcements, an exhibition program, and correspondence. These materials are dated 2011-2019.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/rotimi-fani-kayode
  - Box 69, Folder 9 (Box 69)
- Robert Farber (1948–1995)
  Robert Farber was born in 1948 in Hartsdale, New York. He received a theater degree from Brandeis University, in Waltham, Massachusetts, and spent a year at the London School of Dramatic Art. He later studied art at the Art Students League. His work is in the permanent collections of the Museum of Modern Art and the Victoria and Albert Museum. He passed away in 1995.
  Materials pertaining to Robert Farber were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998 by John Paradiso. They contain exhibition announcements, correspondence, CVs, photocopies of press clippings, artist's statements, photographs of artwork, periodicals, and exhibition catalogs. These materials are dated 1992-1998.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/robert-farber
  - Box 17, Folder 9 (Box 17)
- David Faulk (b. 1963)
  David Faulk was born in 1963 in New York. He studied painting at Syracuse University, as well as in Italy. Many of his paintings feature a character named Lulu. His work has been exhibited in California and New York.
  David Faulk first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2004. They contain exhibition announcements, postcards, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, CVs, artist's statements, photocopies of press clippings, correspondence, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1991-2008.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/david-faulk
  - Box 17, Folder 10 (Box 17)
  - Box 18, Folder 1 (Box 18)
- Tony Feher (1956–2016)
  Tony Feher was born in 1956 in Albuquerque, New Mexico. He received a BA from the University of Texas and then lived in New York City. His practice spanned sculpture, printmaking, and mixed media, often incorporating found materials. His work can be found in the collections of the Guggenheim, the Whitney Museum, the San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, and the Art Institute of Chicago. He passed away in 2016.
  Materials pertaining to Tony Feher donated to the Visual AIDS archive contain memorial materials, correspondence, exhibition announcements, photographs of art, CVs, press releases, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, an artist's statement, press clippings, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1991-2016.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/tony-feher
  - Box 18, Folder 2 (Box 18)
- Arnold Fern (1953–1993)
  Arnold Fern was born in 1952 in Brooklyn, New York. He studied at the Cornell University College of Art and Architecture. He owned three Manhattan restaurants. He primarily produced large oil paintings and worked as a fabric designer. His work has been exhibited in New York and Washington, DC. He passed away in 1993.
  Materials pertaining to Arnold Fern were donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain photographs of artwork, correspondence, exhibition catalogs, CVs, photocopies of press clipping and obituaries, prints of artwork, and 35mm slide documentation of artwork. These materials are dated 1984-1993.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/arnold-fern
  - Box 18, Folder 3 (Box 18)
- Orlando Ferrand-Rodriguez (b. 1967)
  Orlando Ferrand-Rodriguez was born in 1967 in Cuba. He studied at the Instituto Superior de Arte in Havana, Cuba, as well as Parsons School of Design and Pratt Institute in New York. He is a poet and multi-disciplinary artist. His work has been shown in Cuba, Mexico, Spain, Canada, and the US.
  Orlando Ferrand-Rodriguez first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2009. They contain an artist's biography, an artist's statement, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, and a CD with images of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 2004-2008.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/orlando-ferrand
  - Box 18, Folder 4 (Box 18)
- Miguel Ferrando (1957–1996)
  Miguel Ferrando was born in 1957 in Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic. He moved to New York at the age of five and lived there his whole life. He studied at Cooper Union and the Brooklyn Museum Art School. His paintings often blended art historical motifs with references to the Dominican Republic. His work has been exhibited in New York, Zurich, and Mexico City. He passed away in 1996.
  Materials pertaining to Miguel Ferrando were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998 by Teresa Ferrando Kleint. They contain photographic prints of artwork, correspondence, a CV, artist's biographies, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1975-1996.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/miguel-ferrando
  - Box 19, Folder 6 (Box 19)
- Anselmo Figueiredo
  Anselmo Figueiredo has an background in architecture which informs his sculptural work. He sculpts primarily with stone, creating abstract and figurative shapes.
  Materials pertaining to Anselmo Figueiredo donated to the Visual AIDS archive contain an artist's statement, exhibition programs, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1992-1995.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/anselmo-figueiredo
  - Box 18, Folder 5 (Box 18)
- Enrico Filippi (1953–2002)
  Enrico Filippi was born in 1953 in New York. He worked in photography and illustration. He passed away in 2002.
  Enrico Filippi first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1999. They contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials, artist's statement, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1998-2001.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/enrico-filippi
  - Box 18, Folder 6 (Box 18)
- Rich Fine (b. 1986)
  Rich Fine was born in 1986 in Alabama. He received formal training in theatrical design in Chicago, fine craft in Portland, Oregon, and classical painting in New York City. He later apprenticed in Paris. He is a painter who employs a biographically expressionistic style.
  Materials pertaining to Rich Fine include Postcards from the Edge submission materials.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/rich-fine
  - Box 19, Folder 1 (Box 19)
- Robert Flack (1957–1993)
  Robert Flack was born in 1957 in Ontario, Canada. He studied at Sheridan College in Oakville, Ontario, and York University in Toronto. He worked primarily in photography. His work was exhibited in Canada, the US, France, Germany, Japan, and Australia. He passed away in 1993.
  Materials pertaining to Robert Flack were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998 by John Flack. They contain CVs, correspondence, photocopies of press clippings and obituaries, photographic prints of artwork, a CD with images of art, exhibition catalogs, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1990-2000.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/robert-flack
  - Box 19, Folder 2 (Box 19)
- SJ Fleck (b. 1979)
  SJ Fleck was born in 1979 in Detroit, Michigan. He studied at Central Michigan University and Eastern Michigan University, majoring in film with a minor in art photography. He then studied at Oakland University where he learned painting, studio art, and business. His practice spans painting, illustration, screen printing, and photography. He lives and works in Detroit.
  Materials pertaining to SJ Fleck include copies of zines dated 2019.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/sj-fleck
  - Box 69, Folder 8 (Box 69)
- Luis Frangella (1944–1990)
  Luis Frangella was born in 1944 in Buenos Aires. He began to paint in the mid-1970's during a fellowship at MIT's Center for Advanced Visual Studies in Cambridge, Massachusetts. He moved to New York City in 1976, and became part of the burgeoning downtown arts scene. He worked in both painting and sculpture and his work has been exhibited in New York, Buenos Aires, Barcelona, and Madrid. He passed away in 1990.
  Materials pertaining to Luis Frangella were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 2012 by Rosalia Malaccorto Frangella. They contain 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1983-1985.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/luis-frangella
  - Box 19, Folder 4 (Box 19)
- Benjamin Fredrickson (b. 1980)
  Benjamin Fredrickson was born in 1980 in Minneapolis, Minnesota. He studied at the Paris College of Art before earning a BFA from the Minneapolis College of Art and Design. His photography centers on portraiture and subcultural taboos. His work has been exhibited in New York and published widely. He lives and works in Brooklyn.
  Materials pertaining to Benjamin Fredrickson include exhibition announcements and a periodical. These materials are dated 2009-2014.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/benjamin-fredrickson
  - Box 19, Folder 5 (Box 19)
- Martin Freeman (b. 1946)
  Martin Freeman was born in 1946 in Martinez, California. He studied theatre and floristry in San Francisco. His sculptures and paintings have been exhibited in California, New Mexico, and Washington.
  Martin Freeman first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1999. They contain CDs with images of artwork, exhibition announcements, correspondence, art on greeting cards, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, a CV, an artist's statement, calendar submission materials, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1999-2016.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/martin-freeman
  - Box 19, Folder 7 (Box 19)
  - Box 19, Folder 8 (Box 19)
- Jerry Frost (b. 1950)
  Jerry Frost was born in 1950 in Louisville, Kentucky. He received a BA and MA from Chico State University in Chico, California. He works primarily in oil painting. His art has been exhibited in San Francisco and New York.
  Jerry Frost first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2003. They contain CDs with images of art, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, printouts of artwork images, CVs, artist's statements, exhibition announcements, image lists, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 2001-2012.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/jerry-frost
  - Box 20, Folder 1 (Box 20)
  - Box 20, Folder 2 (Box 20)
- Louis Fulgoni (1936–1989)
  Louis Fulgoni was born in 1936 in Staten Island, New York. He studied at the School of Visual Art. He was a graphic artist, print-maker, painter, and sculptor. He passed away in 1989.
  Materials pertaining to Louis Fulgoni were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 2013 by Michael McKee. They contain obituaries and an exhibition press release. These materials are dated 1989-2013.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/louis-fulgoni
  - Box 20, Folder 3 (Box 20)
- Milton Garcia Jr (b. 1970)
  Milton Garcia Jr aka MGNinja was born in 1970 in New York City. He studied at Hostos Community College and the Laboratory Institute of Merchandising. He is an artist, cartoonist, dancer, choreographer, public speaker, and prominent member of New York City's ballroom scene. His work has been exhibited in New York and New Jersey.
  Milton Garcia Jr first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain exhibition announcements, CVs, an artist's biography, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, correspondence, photocopies of artwork, periodicals, a CD with images of art, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1996-2007.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/milton-garcia-ninja
  - Box 20, Folder 6 (Box 20)
  - Box 20, Folder 7 (Box 20)
  - Box B, Folder 14 (Box B)
- Stephen Ten Eyck Gemberling (b. 1947)
  Stephen Gemberling was born in 1947 in York, Pennsylvania. He studied sculpture, architecture, and art history at Cooper Union.
  Stephen Gemberling first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2010. They contain a CD with images of art with accompanying image list, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, and exhibition announcements. These materials are dated 2004-2017.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/stephen-gemberling
  - Box 21, Folder 2 (Box 21)
- Michael Golden (b. 1959)
  Michael Golden was born in 1959 in Fayetteville, North Carolina. He studied at the University of Notre Dame, Washington University, and the University of Texas before completing his MFA in printmaking and drawing at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign. His work has been exhibited widely across the United States. His studio is in Houston where he also curates exhibitions in area galleries.